# ANA LEMOS

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER/ QA ANALYST

- +55 19 98205-5713
- Piracicaba,SP- Brazil
- Linkedin- analemos
- <u>www.analemos.xyz/portfolio/</u>

# PROFILE

Working as an IT professional since 2016, over time I had the opportunity to learn and migrate to some roles such as web developer, execution tester and infrastructure specialist, supporting international and Brazilian clients.

With a generalist profile, I'm very open to reskilling/upskilling and learn tools that could be in need or requested to support the team I belong. At the moment I'm available and looking for new positions after work at IBM and EY.

# SKILLS

- Program languages: Python, JavaScript
- Frameworks/Libraries: Flask, Django, SQLAlchemy, Bootstrap, Node.js, React.
- **Test/Automation:** Selenium, Pytest, SOAP UI, IBM Tivoli Workload Scheduler (TWS), Postman, Insomnia, Jira
- Databases: PostgreSQL, IBM DB2, SQL
- O.S/ Servers: Windows, Linux
- Version control: Git, GitHub
- Others: AWS, EC2, Jenkins, CI/CD, Agile, SaFe, Scrum

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 2023 - 2024

EY, Brazil

#### **Back-End Developer**

The project was a internal web application of a large Brazilian state-owned company created to help analysts verify rules and category of public biddings.

 As a developer I contributed creating new features and refactoring old codes using Python, JavaScript and Flask as framework, was part of sprints planning, schedule of deploys to production, code tests and creating documentation to future reference, support and fix performance issues reported by clients and help team members with less experience.

#### 2022 - 2023

IBM, Hortolândia, Brazil

#### **Test Analyst**

In this project the internal application was responsible to record and present IBM employees profile.

• As a tester I could validate application requirements, sending payloads data to API, using SOAP UI and database queries to compare results expected, was also responsible to create documentation to report success or identified problems.

#### 2021 - 2022

IBM, Hortolândia, Brazil

# **Application Developer**

The AT&T - UB project was a billing application used to calculate all the costs of the services provided by the company, generating invoices that would be sent to clients monthly.

• As a developer/execution tester my roles in team was monitor the execution of UB application in test environment and help team developing the back-end of a dashboard. My daily tasks involved prepare the environment to run using the properly configuration, be aware in case of any error, read outputs, troubleshooting bad behavior of job scheduler or jobs on server, reporting errors on JIRA, communicate and support global test team. Along with monitoring, team had project initiative to automate manually performed processes and display them on a web dashboard, allowing the customer to have more autonomy regarding the status of the tests. In the web project, I was able to help working with Python, creating automatic reports and send them via email and creating routes to send data to the front-end.

### EDUCATION

UNICAMP - UNIVERSIDADE ESTADUAL DE CAMPINAS

• Graduated, Analysis and Development of Systems, 2020

# COURSES/CERTIFICATES

- Python for beginners
- Bootcamp Backend Developer
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals.

In progress:

- Mastering Quality Assurance: Playwright Automated Testing Essentials
- The Complete Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

# LANGUAGES

- Portuguese (Native)
- English (B1/B2)